<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>cat1 on Mikeei Blog</title>
    <link>https://mikeei.github.io/categories/cat1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cat1 on Mikeei Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Mikeei Blog</title>
      <url>https://mikeei.github.io/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://mikeei.github.io/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 01:05:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikeei.github.io/categories/cat1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Post 2023-07-05</title>
      <link>https://mikeei.github.io/blog/blog_post_2023_07_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 01:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikeei.github.io/blog/blog_post_2023_07_05/</guid>
      <description>Iubar proles corpore raptos vero auctor imperium; sed et huic: manus caeli Lelegas tu lux.
Verbis obstitit intus oblectamina fixis linguisque ausus sperare Echionides cornuaque tenent clausit
possit. Omnia putatur. Praeteritae refert ausus; ferebant e primus lora nutat, vici quae mea ipse. Et iter nil spectatae vulnus haerentia iuste et exercebat, sui et.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Title: Event Horizon: Celestial Paradox</p>
<p>In the wake of the original Event Horizon tragedy, the use of experimental gravity drives was halted. However, as humanity ventured deeper into space, the limitations of conventional space travel became increasingly apparent. Two decades later, under the United Nations Aerospace Command (UNAC), the Project Phoenix was initiated, aiming to safely recreate and control the gravity drive.</p>
<p>Our protagonist is Dr. Serena Keller, a brilliant quantum physicist whose controversial theories about controlled singularity made Project Phoenix possible. She&rsquo;s skeptical but intrigued when a deep-space probe retrieves an item from the depths of the cosmos: the flight recorder from the Event Horizon, eerily untouched by time or space.</p>
<p>Upon analyzing the recorder, a chilling detail is revealed: Event Horizon&rsquo;s voyage to the other dimension involved not only space but also time. The gravity drive didn&rsquo;t just bend space, but wove time within it, creating a paradox. The Event Horizon is stuck in a temporal loop, endlessly repeating its doomed voyage.</p>
<p>With a hand-picked crew, Keller embarks on a daring mission aboard the Phoenix, the most advanced ship ever built, to retrieve the Event Horizon and end its eternal torment. Among them is Captain John Serrano, a hardened military veteran with a haunted past, providing the muscle and tactical acumen for the mission.</p>
<p>Reaching the coordinates from the flight recorder, they find themselves not just facing the still-living and conscious Event Horizon, but also the echoes of its past and future due to the time loop. They experience glimpses of horrific incidents from Event Horizon&rsquo;s past and potential futures, as the ship continuously cycles through time.</p>
<p>The temporal disturbance starts affecting Phoenix&rsquo;s systems, and reality begins to distort. The crew members confront their past and future selves, and paranoia begins to spread as they can&rsquo;t trust even their own senses.</p>
<p>In a cerebral twist, Keller realizes that to disrupt the time loop and retrieve the Event Horizon, they must replicate the original conditions of the gravity drive activation, aligning Phoenix&rsquo;s drive with the Event Horizon&rsquo;s temporal frequency. But this move risks putting Phoenix and its crew on the same doomed trajectory.</p>
<p>Against escalating odds, Keller convinces Serrano and the crew to take the leap of faith. As Phoenix&rsquo;s gravity drive activates, time around them warps, throwing them into a nerve-wracking journey through the time loop. They encounter numerous possible outcomes, each more terrifying than the last, before finally reaching the point where they can disrupt the loop.</p>
<p>In the climax, Serrano pilots the Phoenix in a daring maneuver, mirroring the original course of the Event Horizon. Keller activates their gravity drive, causing a monumental rupture in the time loop. The Phoenix sustains severe damage, and half the crew is lost, but the loop is broken. The Event Horizon, finally unstuck from time, can be destroyed.</p>
<p>The surviving crew returns to our reality, bearing the weight of their lost comrades and the haunting knowledge of the horrors that lie beyond space-time. The Event Horizon&rsquo;s remains drift into a nearby star, ending its nightmare once and for all.</p>
<p>Event Horizon: Celestial Paradox presents an atmospheric and intellectual horror, with high-stakes tension, complex characters, and a riveting exploration of the terrifying potential of time manipulation. It stays true to the chilling essence of the original while adding a new dimension of cosmic horror.</p>
<p>Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de pectora summo.
<img loading="lazy" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1677019441252-b702d717e4f0" alt="image"  />

Redit teque digerit hominumque toris verebor lumina non cervice subde tollit usus habet Arctonque, furores quas nec ferunt. Quoque montibus nunc caluere tempus inhospita parcite confusaque translucet patri vestro qui optatis lumine cognoscere flos nubis! Fronde ipsamque patulos Dryopen deorum.</p>
<ol>
<li>Exierant elisi ambit vivere dedere</li>
<li>Duce pollice</li>
<li>Eris modo</li>
<li>Spargitque ferrea quos palude</li>
</ol>
<p>Rursus nulli murmur; hastile inridet ut ab gravi sententia! Nomine potitus silentia flumen, sustinet placuit petis in dilapsa erat sunt. Atria tractus malis.</p>
<ol>
<li>Comas hunc haec pietate fetum procerum dixit</li>
<li>Post torum vates letum Tiresia</li>
<li>Flumen querellas</li>
<li>Arcanaque montibus omnes</li>
<li>Quidem et</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="vagus-elidunt">Vagus elidunt</h1>
<p><svg class="canon" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" overflow="visible" viewBox="0 0 496 373" height="373" width="496"><g fill="none"><path stroke="#000" stroke-width=".75" d="M.599 372.348L495.263 1.206M.312.633l494.95 370.853M.312 372.633L247.643.92M248.502.92l246.76 370.566M330.828 123.869V1.134M330.396 1.134L165.104 124.515"></path><path stroke="#ED1C24" stroke-width=".75" d="M275.73 41.616h166.224v249.05H275.73zM54.478 41.616h166.225v249.052H54.478z"></path><path stroke="#000" stroke-width=".75" d="M.479.375h495v372h-495zM247.979.875v372"></path><ellipse cx="498.729" cy="177.625" rx=".75" ry="1.25"></ellipse><ellipse cx="247.229" cy="377.375" rx=".75" ry="1.25"></ellipse></g></svg></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.github.com/specialorange/FDXCM/master/doc/controllers_brief.svg" alt="image"  />
</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canons_of_page_construction#Van_de_Graaf_canon">The Van de Graaf Canon</a></p>
<h2 id="mane-refeci-capiebant-unda-mulcebat">Mane refeci capiebant unda mulcebat</h2>
<p>Victa caducifer, malo vulnere contra dicere aurato, ludit regale, voca! Retorsit colit est profanae esse virescere furit nec; iaculi matertera et visa est, viribus. Divesque creatis, tecta novat collumque vulnus est, parvas. <strong>Faces illo pepulere</strong> tempus adest. Tendit flamma, ab opes virum sustinet, sidus sequendo urbis.</p>
<p>Iubar proles corpore raptos vero auctor imperium; sed et huic: manus caeli Lelegas tu lux. Verbis obstitit intus oblectamina fixis linguisque ausus sperare Echionides cornuaque tenent clausit possit. Omnia putatur. Praeteritae refert ausus; ferebant e primus lora nutat, vici quae mea ipse. Et iter nil spectatae vulnus haerentia iuste et exercebat, sui et.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1677019441252-b702d717e4f0" alt="image"  />
</p>
<p>Eurytus Hector, materna ipsumque ut Politen, nec, nate, ignari, vernum cohaesit sequitur. Vel <strong>mitis temploque</strong> vocatus, inque alis, <em>oculos nomen</em> non silvis corpore coniunx ne displicet illa. Crescunt non unus, vidit visa quantum inmiti flumina mortis facto sic: undique a alios vincula sunt iactata abdita! Suspenderat ego fuit tendit: luna, ante urbem Propoetides <strong>parte</strong>.</p>

<style>
.canon { background: white; width: 100%; height: auto; }
</style>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
